Guide to the Max Lincoln Schuster Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Max Lincoln Schuster Papers,
[ca. 1913-1976]
Schuster, M. Lincoln (Max Lincoln), 1897-1970.
300 boxes
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079317
History
Publisher. Schuster was co-founder and chairman of the board of Simon & Schuster, Inc.
Scope and Content
Schuster's correspondence including letters from authors Bernard Berenson, Will and Ariel Durant, Max Eastman, Nikos Kazantzakis, Max Lerner, Henry Miller, Bertrand Russell, and Louis Untermeyer; advertisements and other material relating to Pocket Books, Inc. which was owned by Simon & Schuster; and an author and title file containing correspondence, comments, and reviews of Simon & Schuster publications, and miscellaneous notes, clippings, photographs, manuscripts, and printed material.
Subjects
Simon and Schuster, inc.; Berenson, Bernard, 1865-1959.; Durant, Will, 1885-1981.; Durant, Ariel.; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969.; Kazantzakis, Nikos, 1883-1957.; Lerner, Max, 1902-1992.; Miller, Henry, 1891-1980.; Russell, Bertrand, 1872-1970.; Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-1977.; Pocket editions.; Publishers and publishing.; Literature publishing.; Literature.
Access Restrictions
This collection is housed on site.
Acquisition
1971 M-71 Schuster, Mrs. M. L. Gift
Alternate Formats
Pearl S. Buck letter is on microfilm.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Aga Khan III, (12 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Annenberg, Walter H., (3 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Baldwin Roger Nash, (2 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Baruch, Bernard Mannes, (22 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Beard, Charles Austin, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Beerbohm, Max, (10 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Behrman, Samuel Nathaniel, (2 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Ben-Gurion, David, (3 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Berenson, Bernhard, (34 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Berg, Gertrude, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Berlin, Irving, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Berlin, Isaih, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Bliven, Bruce, (2 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Block, Herbert Lawrence ("Herblock"), (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Bourke-White, Margaret, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Bowers, Claude Gernade, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Bowers, Claude G., (7 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Bowles, Chester, (2 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Buchwald, Art, (6 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Buck, Pearl S., (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Burns, George, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Bush, Douglas, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Cantor, Eddie, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Cerf, Bennett Alfred, (5 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Chayefsky, Paddy, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Churchill, Winston Spencer, (2 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Giradi, John, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Commanger, Henry Steel, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Cook, Alistair, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Cortissoz, Royal, (2 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Cousins, Norman, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Coward, Noel, (2 Folders) (Box 1)
  - Craven, Thoams, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Cunliffe, John, (1 Folder) (Box 1)
  - Davies, Joseph Edward, (2 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Dell, Floyd, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Dietz, Howard, (4 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Dollar, Robert, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Dorfman, Ania, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Douglas, William Orville, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Downing, Augusta S., (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Dreiser, Theodore, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Dubois, William Edward Burghardt, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Durant, Ariel, (3 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Durant, Will, (14 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Durant, Will and Ariel, (17 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Earle, Edward Mead, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Eastman, Max, (10 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Edman, Irwin, (5 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Endore, Guy, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Erdman, Charles Rosenburg, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Ernst, Morris Leopold, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Everett, Roberts, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Fadiman, Clifton, (7 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Ferber, Edna, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Field, Marshall, III, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Flexner, Abraham, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Freeman, Joseph, (3 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Friar, Kimon, (6 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Fuessle, Newton Augusta, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Garrison, Lloyd Kirkham, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Gassner, John Waldhorn, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Geffen, Maxwell Myles, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Gilbert, Cass, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Gish, Lillian, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Golden, Harry, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Goldwyn, Samuel, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Gray, Gilda, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Green, Anna Katharina, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Grew, David, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Guiterman, Arthur, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Hadley, Arthur Twining, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Haldeman-Julius, Emanuel, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Hale, Beatrice Forbes-Robertson, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Hall, Leland, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Halsey, Margaret Frances, (2 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Halsman, Phillips, (2 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Hapgood, Hutchins and Scully, Frank, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Hapgood, Norman, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Harriman, William Averell, (3 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Hart, William S., (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Hays, Arthur Garfield, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Hazlitt, Henry, (2 Folders) (Box 2)
  - Heaton, John Langdon, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Hellinger, Mark, (1 Folder) (Box 2)
  - Halsman, Philippe, (4 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Hammerstein, Oscar II, (3 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Hand, Learned, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Handlin, Oscar, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Hansen, Harry, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Harriman, William Averell, (23 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Hayes, Carlton J.H., (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Hellman, Lillian, (2 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Hemingway, Ernest (1 Folder), (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Hersey, John, (3 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Hoover, John Edgar, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Hopper, Hedda, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Hough, Henry Beetle, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Humphrey, Hubert Horatio, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Isham, Ralph Heyward, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Javits, Jacob K., (2 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Jessel, George, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Josephine Winslow, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Johnson, Lyndon Baines, (5 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Kazan, Elia, (2 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Kazantzakis, Eleni Samios, (28 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Kazantzakis, Nikos, (51 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Keller, Helen, (2 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Keller, Helen S., (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Kennedy, John Fitzgerald, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Kennedy, Robert Francis, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Knopf, Alfred A., (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Knopf, Blanche, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Kollek, Theodore, (1 Folder) (Box 3)
  - Krock, Arthur, (2 Folders) (Box 3)
  - Landon, Alf M., (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Lasker, Mary, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Lehman, Herbert H., (8 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Lenya, Lotte, (2 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Lerner, Max, (54 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Levenson, Sam, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Lippman, Walter, (3 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Loewe, Frederick, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Lovejoy, Clarence Earle, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Luce, Clare Boothe, (2 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Luce, Henry R., (2 Folders) (Box 4)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, (2 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Mann, Thomas, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - March, Frederic, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Mariano, Nicky, (10 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Mariano, Elizabeth, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Mariano, Nicky, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Mariano, Elizabettta, (6 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Marx, "Groucho" Julius, (16 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Masefield, John, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Mass, Roslyn, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Masters, Edgar Lee, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Maugham, William Somerset, (2 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Mencken, Henry Louis, (11 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Miller, Arthur, (6 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Miller, Henry, (23 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Montagu, Ashley, (6 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Morganthau, Henry, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Morley, Christopher, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Moses, Robert, (9 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Muggeridge, Malcolm, (1 Folder) (Box 4)
  - Murrow, Edward R., (2 Folders) (Box 4)
  - Nash, Ogden, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Nathan, Georges Jean, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Nevins, Allan, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Niebuhr, Reinhold, (3 Folders) (Box 5)
  - Noyes, Alfred, (2 Folders) (Box 5)
  - Palmer, Robert Roswell, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Pearson, Drew, (2 Folders) (Box 5)
  - Peattie, Donald Culross, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Pitkin, Walter Boughton, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Porter, Cole, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Potter, Charles Francis, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Powys, John Cowper, (11 Folders) (Box 5)
  - Pulitzer, Joseph Jr., (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Rahv, Philip, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Renault, Mary, (2 Folders) (Box 5)
  - Reston, James Barrett, (2 Folders) (Box 5)
  - Reynolds, Quentin, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Rexroth, Kenneth, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Rice, Elmer, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Rockefeller, John D. II, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Rockefeller, John D. III, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Rodgers, Richard, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor, (6 Folders) (Box 5)
  - Roosevelt, James, (2 Folders) (Box 5)
  - Rose, Billy, (3 Folders) (Box 5)
  - Rosenman, Samuel Irving, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Ross, Harold W., (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Rosset, Barney, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Ruark, Robert C., (2 Folders) (Box 5)
  - Russell, Bertrand, (71 Folders) (Box 5)
  - Rustin, Bayard, et al., (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Ryskind, Morrie, (1 Folder) (Box 5)
  - Sanger, Margaret, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Sarnoff, David, (14 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Schiff, Dorothy, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Schirra, Walter M. Jr., (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur Jr., (3 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Schoenman, Ralph, (3 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Schuster, Max Lincoln, (2 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Schweitzer, Albert, (2 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Schnabel, Arthur, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Selznick, David O., (3 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Sermolino, Maria, (2 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Sheen, Vincent, (2 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Shepard, Alan B. Jr., (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Shirer, William Lawrence, (5 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Shotwell, James T., (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Simon, Richard Leo, (3 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Sitwell, Osbert, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Skouras, Spyros P., (3 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Skouras, Spyros S., (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Smith, Thomas R., (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Sorensen, Theodore Chaikin, (2 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Stevenson, Adlai E., (9 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Stidger, William Leroy, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Stimson, Henry L., (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Stout, Rex, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Sulzberg, Arthur Hays, (5 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard, (4 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Taylor, Alan John Percivale, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Taylor, Telford, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Lowell, Thomas, (2 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Thomas, Norman, (2 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Thurber, James, (3 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Tinker, Chauncey Brewster, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Trevelyan, George Macaulay, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Trilling, Lionel, (3 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Trotsky, Leon, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Truman, Harry S., (11 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Tuchman, Barbara, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Untermeyer, Louis, (18 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Untermeyer, Louis and Bryan, (3 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Unwin, Sir Stanley, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Carl Clinton, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Irita, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Van Doren, Mark, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Van Loon, Hendrik William, (3 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Wagner, Robert Jr., (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Warren, Earl, (6 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Werfel, Franz, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Whitney, John Hay, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Winchell, Walter, (3 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Wodehouse, Pelham Grenville, (1 Folder) (Box 6)
  - Wouk, Herman, (4 Folders) (Box 6)
  - Ackerman, Carl William, (4 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Acton, Harold Mario, (4 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Acton, Hortense Mitchell, (5 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Adler, Elmer, (5 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Aga Khan III, (4 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Allen, Henry Justin, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Aly Khan, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Annenberg, Walter, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Anrep, Alda Mariano, Baroness, (8 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Anthony, Edward, (3 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Atherton, Gertrude, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Atwood, Albert William, (3 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Austin, Mary Hunter, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Baruch, Barnard Mannes, (2 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Barzun, Jacques, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Beebe, William, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Beerbohm, Elisabeth Jungmann (Lady), (6 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Beerbohm, Max, (2 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Bemelmans, Ludwig, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Behrman, Samuel Nathaniel, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Benton, William, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Berenson, Bernard, (31 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Berenson, Lawrence, (2 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Berlin, Sir Isaiah, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Bernays, Edward L., (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Björkman, Edwin August. "The Ten Books I have Enjoyed the Most." (Box 245)
  - Blitzstein, Marc, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Bok, Edward William, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Boyd, Ernest Augustus, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Brady, William A., (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Brentano, Lowell, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Bryan, William Jennings, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Buchwald, Art, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Burgess, Gelett. "The Ten Books I have Enjoyed the Most." (Box 245)
  - Burrought, Edgar Rice, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Burrows, Abe, (2 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Carrier, Louis, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Case, Frank, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Cerf, Bennett Alfred, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Chambers, Lenoir, (3 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Chaplin, Charles. Charles Chaplin’s Autobiography (Box 245)
  - Cini, Vittorio, (2 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Clarkin, Franklin, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Claus, Henry Turner, (4 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Cobb, Irvin Shrewsbury, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Cook, Joe, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Cooke, Alistair, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Cooper, Douglas, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Cosgrave, John O’Hara, (5 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Cousins, Norman, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Craven, Thomas, (4 Folders) (Box 245)
  - Craven, Thomas. Photograph (Box 245)
  - Cross, Wilbur Lucius, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Crowther, Bosley, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - Curley, James Michael, (1 Folder) (Box 245)
  - De Gaulle, Charles, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - de Kruif, Paul, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Deutsch, Babette, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Dewey, Godfrey, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Dietz, Howard, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Douglas, William O., (5 Folders) (Box 246)
  - Dowling, Eddie, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Durant, Ariel, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Durant, Will, (52 Folders) (Box 246)
  - Durante, James (Jimmy), (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Eastman, Max, (18 Folders) (Box 246)
  - Edman, Irwin, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Einstein, Albert, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Eisenhower, Dwight David, (4 Folders) (Box 246)
  - Eliot, Thomas Stearns, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Ellison, Ralph, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Erskine, Helen Worden, (2 Folders) (Box 246)
  - Fadiman, Clifton, (6 Folders) (Box 246)
  - Fairbanks, Douglas Jr., (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Ferber, Edna, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Ferré, Louis, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Feuchtwanger, Lion, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Finletter, Thomas K., (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Fitzgerald, Francis Scott Key. "The Ten Books I have Enjoyed the Most." (Box 246)
  - Flanner, Janet, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Flexner, Abraham, (2 Folders) (Box 246)
  - Frank, Jerome New, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Frankfurter, Felix, (2 Folders) (Box 246)
  - Freeman, Joseph, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Friar, Kimon, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Fulbright, James William, (5 Folders) (Box 246)
  - Gabrilowitsch, Clara Clemens, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Galantiére, Lewis, (2 Folders) (Box 246)
  - Gallico, Paul W., (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Gary, Romain, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Gassner, John Waldhorn, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Gershwin, Ira, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Glenn, John H. Jr., (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Golden, Harry, (2 Folders) (Box 246)
  - Goldwyn, Samuel, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Goodman, Benny, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Gunther, John, (1 Folder) (Box 246)
  - Hobson, Laura Z., (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Holliday, Robert Cortes. "The Ten Books I have Enjoyed the Most." (Box 247)
  - Hook, Sidney, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Horn, Alfred Aloysius Smith ("Trader Horn") (Box 247)
  - Horn, Alfred Aloysius Smith ("Trader Horn"). Photograph (Box 247)
  - Hough, Clara Sharpe, (5 Folders) (Box 247)
  - Hough, George Anthony, (14 Folders) (Box 247)
  - Hough, Henry Beetle, (2 Folders) (Box 247)
  - Huebsch, Ben W., (3 Folders) (Box 247)
  - Huff, Louise, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Hurst, Fannie, (7 Folders) (Box 247)
  - Hurst, Fannie. "The Ten Books I Have Enjoyed Most." (Box 247)
  - Hutchins, Robert Maynard. "An Early Treatise on Education." (Box 247)
  - Ingersoll, Ralph McAllister, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Ingram, Rex, (2 Folders) (Box 247)
  - Isham, Ralph Heyward, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Jackson, Joseph Henry, (2 Folders) (Box 247)
  - Javits, Jacob Koppel, (2 Folders) (Box 247)
  - Johnson, Edgar, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Johnson, Gerald White, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Kazantzakis, Eleni Samios, (19 Folders) (Box 247)
  - Kazantzakis, Nikos, (4 Folders) (Box 247)
  - Kelland, Clarence Budington. "The Ten Books I have Enjoyed the Most." (Box 247)
  - Kemp, Harry Hibbard. "The Ten Books I have Enjoyed the Most." (Box 247)
  - Kerr, Sophie, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Kline, Burton, (2 Folders) (Box 247)
  - Kolleck, Theodore, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Kostelanetz, Andre, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Lasker, Mary Woodward, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Lerner, Max, (2 Folders) (Box 247)
  - Levin, Meyer, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Lewisohn, Ludwig. "The Ten Books I have Enjoyed the Most." (Box 247)
  - Lincoln, Charles Monroe, (2 Folders) (Box 247)
  - Liveright, Horace Brisbin, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Lloyd, Harold, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Longwell, Daniel, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Loveman, Amy, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Lovejoy, Clarence Earle, (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Lowell, Joan (pseud.), (1 Folder) (Box 247)
  - Mcadoo, William Gibbs, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - MacAlarney, Robert Emmet, (6 Folders) (Box 248)
  - McEvoy, Joseph Patrick, (2 Folders) (Box 248)
  - MacMonnie, Frederick, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Macy, George, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Mariano, Nicky, (29 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Marshall, James, (4 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Marshall, Leonore, (3 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Martin, George, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Marx, Julius "Groucho", (3 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Meir, Golda, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Mencken, Henry Louis, (5 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Menuhin, Yehudi. Photograph of Bernard Berenson "Last picture taken of B.B." (Box 248)
  - Miller, Arthur, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Miller, Henry, (5 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Morgenthau, Henry, Jr., (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Moses, Robert, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Moyer, Charles Edward, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Nathan, George Jean, (2 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Newlin, William Jesse, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - O’Brien, Frederick, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Overton, Grant Martin, (2 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Paine, Albert Bigelow. "The Ten Books I Have Enjoyed Most" (Box 248)
  - Pitkin, Walter Boughton, (14 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Post, Marjorie Merriweather, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Pulitzer, Ralph, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Roscoe, Burton, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Reston, James Barrett, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Reynaud, Christiane Mabire, (2 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Reynaud, Paul, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Rich, Edwin Gile, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Ripley, Robert LeRoy, (2 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Robinson, Henry Morton, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Roderick, Stella Virginia, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Rome, Harold Jacob, (2 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Rose, Billy and Lester Avnet, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Rosenberg, James Naumburg, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Roseman, Samuel Irving, (4 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Ross, David, (2 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Russell, Bertrand, (3 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Ryskind, Morrie, (3 Folders) (Box 248)
  - St. John, Robert, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Santayana, George, (1 Folder) (Box 248)
  - Sarnoff, David, (3 Folders) (Box 248)
  - Scherman, Bernardine Kielty, (4 Folders) (Box 249)
  - Scherman, Harry and Bernardine K., (2 Folders) (Box 249)
  - Scherman, Harry, (3 Folders) (Box 249)
  - Schiff, Dorothy, (1 Folder) (Box 249)
  - Scully, Frank, (114 Folders) (Box 249)
  - Simon, Richard Leo, (21 Folders) (Box 250)
  - Sinclair, Upton, (1 Folder) (Box 250)
  - Sitwell, Dame Edith, (1 Folder) (Box 250)
  - Shirer, William Lawrence, (3 Folders) (Box 250)
  - Shipman, Samuel, (1 Folder) (Box 250)
  - Sherman, Stuart Pratt, (1 Folder) (Box 250)
  - Serlin, Oscar, (1 Folder) (Box 250)
  - Smith, H. Allen, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Sokolsky, George Ephraim, (5 Folders) (Box 251)
  - Sondheim, Stephen, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Standley, William Harrison, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Steinmetz, Charles Proteus, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Stern, Philip Van Doren, (2 Folders) (Box 251)
  - Stokowski, Leopold, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Sulzberger, Iphigene Ochs, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Sunday, William Ashley "Billy", (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard, (15 Folders) (Box 251)
  - Thomas, Lowell, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Toklas, Alice B., (11 Folders) (Box 251)
  - Tolstoy, Alexandra L., (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Troubetzkoy, Amélie Rives, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Tumulty, Joseph Patrick, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, (2 Folders) (Box 251)
  - Untermeyer, Louis, (7 Folders) (Box 251)
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, (2 Folders) (Box 251)
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem. "Heil MLS!" Ink and watercolor (Box 251)
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem. "The Ten Books I Have Enjoyed Most" (Box 251)
  - Van Loon, Hendrik Willem. "Welcome to Max" Ink and watercolor (Box 251)
  - Wadsworth, James Wolcott, Jr., (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Waley, Arthur, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Walpole, Hugh. "Ten Books" (Box 251)
  - Wagner, Walter F., (3 Folders) (Box 251)
  - Watson, Thomas J., Jr., (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Weaver, John Van Alstyn, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Weidman, Jerome, (3 Folders) (Box 251)
  - Werth, Alexander, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Wheeler, Hoard Duryee, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - White, William Allen, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Whitney, John Hay, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Williams, Tascott, (5 Folders) (Box 251)
  - Woodberry, George Edward, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Winchell, Walter, (1 Folder) (Box 251)
  - Young, Stark. "Ten Books" (Box 251)
- Series II: Catalogued Manuscripts and Documents
  - Benet, Stephen Vincent "Dear Adolph"-A Letter to Hitler (Box 7)
  - Benet, Stephen Vincent. "Speech for Raymond Massey" (Box 7)
  - Bowen, Catherine Drinker. "Address at National Book Awards" (Box 7)
  - Buck, Pearl S. "Red Srar over China by Edgar Snow" (Box 7)
  - Cheever, John. "Address at National Book Awards" (Box 7)
  - Compton, Arthur Holly. "Give Us Vision!" (Box 7)
  - De Valera, Eamon. "A Conversation with Eamon De Valera" (Box 7)
  - Durant, Will and Ariel. "Confessions" (Box 7)
  - Durant, Will. "A Philosophy of Life for Our Times." (Box 7)
  - Eastman, Max. "Press Interview on History of the Russion Revolution." (Box 7)
  - Edman, Irwin. "Acquiescence" (Box 7)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield. "Remarks on Refugees" (Box 7)
  - Hughes, Langston. "Simple Speaks His Mind." (Box 7)
  - Jarrell, Randall. "About Popular Culture." (Box 7)
  - Lanowska, Wanda. "A Conversation with Wanda Ladowska." (Box 7)
  - Laski, Harols J. "Can Capitalism or Socialism Promote a Better Society?" (Box 7)
  - Malamud, Bernard. "Address at National Book Awards" (Box 7)
  - Mannes, Marya. "Address at National Book Awards" (Box 7)
  - Maugham, W. Somerset. "Preface to The Memoirs of Aga Khan." (Box 7)
  - Mumford, Lewis. "The Philosophy of Storage" (Box 7)
  - Oppenheimer, Robert. "The Scientist in Society." (Box 7)
  - Plaut, Abraham Lincoln. "Robert Moses." (Box 7)
  - Priestley, J. B. "Review of Aldous Huxley’s Ends and Means> (Box 7)
  - Powys, John Cowper. "Dostoevsky" (Box 7)